Guide to the György Kepes papers M1796
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 9. Kepes in magazines [chronological]
  Published references to Kepes and his work, especially reviews of his books and exhibitions, but also brief mentions. Many also reproduce his photographs and artwork. Includes clippings and full issues from magazines and journals as well as auction catalogs and other printed material. More can be found throughout the collection. See also "Kepes writing, published" for articles with text by Kepes.
  - undated (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - 1945-1958 (Box 130, Folders 2-4)
  - 1959-1966 (Box 131, Folders 1-4)
  - 1967-1972 (Box 132, Folders 1-3)
  - 1973-2005 (Box 133, Folders 1-6)
  - articles mounted on cardboard (Box 190, Folder 4)
- Series 10. Published writing [chronological]
  Articles, essays, and other writing by Kepes, as printed in magazines such as Arts & Architecture, Art in America, Daedalus, and Leonardo. Other examples may be found throughout the collection.
  - undated (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - 1947-1959 (Box 124, Folders 2-4)
  - 1960-1961 (Box 125, Folder 1)
  - 1965 (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - 1966-1971 (Box 127, Folders 1-3)
  - 1972-1977 (Box 128, Folders 1-2)
  - 1980-1986 (Box 129, Folder 1)
- Series 11. New Bauhaus/Institute of Design
  - Maholy-Nagy, School of Design proposal (photocopy), 1939-01-17 (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - page from magazine with Kepes image and Maholy-Nagy text re: Kepes, 1940 (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - Institute of Design press release for Kepes exhibition, 1943 (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - New Bauhaus promotional booklet (Box 189, Folder 7)
- Series 12. MIT/Center for Advanced Visual Studies
  - 12.1. MIT/CAVS publications etc.
    - undated (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - 1950-1971 (Box 134, Folders 2-5)
    - 1972-1981 (Box 135, Folders 1-3)
    - 1982-2002 (Box 136, Folders 1-3)
  - 12.2. MIT/ CAVS files
    Correspondence, memoranda, reports, journals, course catalogs, exhibition material, brochures, and other material related to the Massachusetts Institute of Technology and the Center for Advanced Visual Studies.
    - Center Material, 1963-1981 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      Correspondence between Kepes and others, including Otto Piene and other artists.
    - Memorandum to Fellows from Kepes, 1971-08-10 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      Memo to Fellows of the Center for Advanced Visual Studies about various financial and historical issues.
    - Center For Advanced Visual Studies, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      Paper by Kepes on the purpose and goals of the Center for Advanced Visual Studies.
    - 1972-73 Report to the President, 1973-07-20 (Box 17, Folder 19)
      Kepes report to the President of MIT on the Center for Advanced Visual Studies.
    - MIT Environmental Design Study (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1984 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      Correspondence mostly related to MIT business. Includes a letter of recommendation. Some material in Hungarian.
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      Correspondence, mostly concerning the Center for Advanced Visual Studies, as well as correspondence between Kepes and Otto Piene of the Center for Advanced Research Studies.
    - Center for Advanced Visual Studies, 1967-1974 (Box 27, Folder 31)
      Correspondence and printed material relating to the Center for Advanced Visual Studies and its activities in Boston.
    - Center for Advanced Studies Research Fellows (Box 28, Folder 9)
      Printed descriptions of installation works done by artists Maryanne Amacher, Luis Frangella, Lowry Burgess, Joe Moss, and Paul Earls.
    - Graduate Study in Architecture at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Box 28, Folder 35)
      Publicity material for a Master's of Architecture at MIT.
    - Council for the Arts at MIT - Annual Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Don Snyder, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 19)
      Two syllabi and a resume for MIT instructor Don Snyder.
    - Lightgraphics and Photographics (Box 29, Folder 16)
      Syllabus for a course taught by Don Snyder.
    - CAS Correspondence, 1992 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      Correspondence from various people to Charles M. Vest, President of MIT, appealing to keep the Center for Advanced Studies autonomous.
    - CAVS Centerbeam report (Box 105, Folder 8)
    - MIT press release on CAVS funding, 1971-12-13 (Box 105, Folder 9)
    - MIT Compton Gallery guestbook, 1986 (Box 105, Folder 10)
    - MIT Program in Art, Culture and Technology materials, 2010 (Box 105, Folder 11)
    - MIT miscellaneous (Box 105, Folder 11)
- Series 13. Transcripts
  - 13.1. Lectures, interview transcripts & notes
    - Light Lecture Notes (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Hand-written notes and typed material.
    - Lectures by Kepes and Others 1969, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Contains typescripts of various lectures, some with Kepes's hand-written notes. Other names include: John Ruskin, Galileo Galilei, Vincent Van Gogh, and James Rosser Johnson.
    - Notes and Lecture on Modern Art (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Original folder labeled "Charles Center" - undated lecture does not appear to be related.
    - Notes for a Lecture in Los Angeles (Box 16, Folder 15)
      Material appears to be rough notes for a lecture - topics include politics, academia, and light.
    - Lecture Celebrations (Box 25, Folder 11)
      Hand-corrected typescripts on art, including Hungarian folk art, in English and Hungarian.
    - Berlin Lecture, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 16)
      Folder is labeled that these files relate to a lecture Kepes gave in Berlin in October 1973. Contains fragments of various printed materials, but no complete lecture.
    - Interview transcript, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 13)
      Interview between Kepes and Rudolph deHarak in Boston, March 31, 1987.
    - Images of Cities and The Environment in the Visual Arts, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      Syllabus to a course Kepes co-taught with Lloyd Rodwin in Spring 1984.
    - Interview, 1969-1970 (Box 30, Folder 22)
      Pages from a transcript of an interview between "K" (Kepes?) and "T." (Takis?) Various pages, some with hand-written notes.
    - Color/Light/Architecture (Box 30, Folder 30)
      Poster for a lecture series of which Kepes was a part.
    - Interview, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      Several partial copies of an interview between "K" (Kepes?) and "T" (Takis?).
    - Private and Civic Art (Box 38, Folder 7)
      Typescript of a paper given at Brighton College. Presumably by Kepes.
    - Lecture, Photography, 1978 (Box 38, Folder 12)
      Handwritten notes.
    - Dewey Society Lecture, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 7)
      Typescript of a lecture.
    - Speech (Box 58, Folder 3)
      Photocopy, with handwritten notes, of a speech Kepes gave.
    - pre-1 (Box 58, Folder 5)
      Photocopy of a heavily hand-corrected typsecript, apparently of a lecture.
    - Berlin Lecture, Art in Civic Scale (Box 58, Folder 15)
    - Lecture notes (Box 58, Folder 14)
      Outline-format lecture notes.
    - printed material: lectures, speeches, appearances (Box 105, Folder 13)
  - 13.2. Kepes/Takis transcripts
    - Re-edited and Re-typed, 1970-06 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      Corrected typescript of an interview between Kepes and Takis. Typescript is actually dated 2/27/1969. Original folder title.
    - Edited June 70, typed 6/70, 1970 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      Typescripts of Kepes/Takis interview.
    - Early Dialogue Tapes Copy to Be Edited (Box 44, Folder 3)
      Two copies of a typescript.
    - Dialogues (Box 44, Folder 4)
      Typescripts.
    - Edited Dialogues, 1969-10 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Carbon of Tape Text, Oct. 29-Nov. 4 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Original Dialogue, 1969-10 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Index Strips, 0 dictation belt(s) (Box 44, Folder 8)
      Gray Magnetic Belt inserts. Originally in an envelope labeled "Takis/Kepes Dialogues. Completed Tapes (typed)."
    - Original Dialogues, 1969-1970 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Dialogue Transcribed, 1970-09-01 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Dialogue, 1969-03 (Box 44, Folder 11)
      Typescript.
    - Original of Tape Text, Oct. 29 - Nov. 4 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Edited Dialogue, 1969-03 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Dialogue, 1969-02 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Dialogue (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Oct. 29-Nov. 4 Edited (not final) (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Typescripts (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - Dialogue, Edited, 1969-02 (Box 44, Folder 18)
- Series 14. Correspondence
  Includes correspondence concerning galleries, loans, permissions, personal matters, etc. Some printed material is also present.
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Correspondence from G. Kepes re: crediting MIT students in publicity, from Ted Kraynick re: Light Tower proposal, and cover sheet titled "Proposal for an Acoustic Oasis" by James R. Taggart.
  - Letter from Nathan Lerner to "Charlie", 1981-09-24 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    One-page letter from photographer Lerner to "Charlie" (?) about Kepes and his importance to modern and and design, as well as art education.
  - Correspondence from Ockenga, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    Two letters to Kepes from Starr Ockenga, about Kepes's contribution to a journal called POSITIVE.
  - Correspondence and Files 1987, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Correspondence consists of letters of recommendation by Kepes. Other files are copies of published materials, and do not seem to relate to the correspondence.
  - Correspondence, 1976-1989 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Correspondence pertaining to business, especially exhibitions, image permissions, and professional courtesies - some material in Hungarian.
  - Correspondence, 1965-1987 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    Correspondence, mostly about exhibitions and lectures. Some personal correspondence. One item in Hungarian, one in German.
  - Correspondence, 1958-1988 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    Correspondence, primarily business in nature. Also interspersed are a newspaper clipping and other printed material. Includes items in Hungarian.
  - Correspondence, Printed Material, Notes 1986-1987, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
    Correspondence is mostly with galleries. Notes and printed material are similar to previous instances. Significant amount of material is in Hungarian.
  - Correspondence, 1958-1989 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    Bulk 1980s. Mostly correspondence with galleries and curators about sales and exhibitions.
  - Correspondence and Printed Material 1965, 1972, 1986-1987, undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
    Correspondence, mostly about exhibitions and other professional activities, interspersed with printed material that is similar to much of the other printed material spread throughout this series.
  - Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    Includes a letter of recommendation. Some material in Hungarian.
  - Printed Material and Correspondence, 1970-1997 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    Much of the correspondence has to do with the Poetry mailer. Other topics include computers, art and Kepes' travel.
  - Arts Organizations, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    Correspondence and other materials related to various arts organizations, including International Directory of Arts, The Club of Rome, World Institute of Arts and Letters, and the National Institute of Arts and Letters.
  - Correspondence and Miscellaneous Files 1973-1974, undated (Box 27, Folder 13)
    Includes correspondence pertaining to the publication "Contemporary Artists."
  - Correspondence, incoming, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    Incoming letters to Kepes - subjects include a printing company invoice, exhibitions, The National Institute of Arts and Letters, a conference called Art Transition, and the dissertation work of several students as the Bezalel Academy of Arts and Design in Jerusalem, as well as a handwritten note from Jonathan Burks about subletting a studio space.
  - Correspondence, photographs, etc. 1987, undated (Box 27, Folder 27)
    Photographic prints, correspondence with Massachusetts College of Art and Clarence Kennedy Gallery, and other material.
  - Correspondence and Art 1979, 1982, 2005 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    Contains envelope and cancelled stamps, correspondence from artist Michio Ihara as well as a local television producer. Also contains a small (3x5) watercolor signed by "Haj" on November 11, 1979. "Haj" may refer to MIT linguist John Robert Ross (Haj was apparently his nickname). Materials do not seem to be all that related, but appeared near one another.
  - Thank-you card, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    Hand-drawn card to Kepes from the University of Cincinnati's 1980 Graphic Design class.
  - Television Studies Proposal (Box 28, Folder 21)
    Proposal by Colin McCurdie, a graduate student in Harvard's Department of Education, to teach an undergraduate course in television studies.
  - Correspondence, 1975, 1999 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    Two postcards and a long letter about goats, author unknown.
  - Correspondence, 1983-1987 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    Includes an exhibition brochure for Otto Piene.
  - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    Correspondence and clipping regarding the McDermott award and possible collaboration between Kepes and Dr. Jaroslav Cervenka, a dentistry professor at the University of Minnesota.
  - Correspondence, 1968, 1972, undated (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence and printed material, 1971-1986 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence and Printed Material, 1980s (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1989 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    Assorted correspondence, related to MIT affairs as well as various professional organizations.
  - Correspondence, 1966-1979 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Evá Körner, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    Correspondence between Kepes and Korner. Some in Hungarian.
  - Correspondence, 1954-1979 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    Bulk 1970s.
  - Correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1983 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    Some material in Italian and Hungarian.
  - Correspondence, Leonard Currie, 1995-1996 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    Correspondence between Kepes and Currie.
  - Correspondence, 1974-1986 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    Three letters.
  - Correspondence, 1952-1996 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    Bulk 1970s and 1980s. Large amount of correspondence, some of which is in Hungarian, German, and Chinese.
  - Correspondence, 1975-1998 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence (Letters to Answer), 1989 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1990 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1986 (Box 32, Folder 21)
    Bulk 1970s and 1980s. Some material is in German, Italian, Hungarian.
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    One letter is in French.
  - Correspondence, 1964-1979 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    Bulk 1970s. Significant amount of material in Hungarian.
  - Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1982 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1983, 1989 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    A few items in French, Hungarian, and German.
  - Correspondence: Possible Commitments, 1973-1974 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1988 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1978 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1958-1978 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    Originally in a foldered labeled "Bury." Bulk 1970s, large amount 1977.
  - Correspondence, Bill FitzGibbons, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 12)
    Letter and two photographs from artist Bill FitzGibbons.
  - Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Tungsram, 1978-1979 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - School of Fine Arts, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, European Friends, 1979-1981 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence and Printed Material, 1948-1976 (Box 33, Folder 21)
    Mostly correspondence. Bulk 1950s and 1960s.
  - Correspondence, 1952-1977 (Box 33, Folder 22)
    Bulk 1950s
  - Correspondence and printed material, 1985-1989 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence and Clippings, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    Some material in German.
  - Correspondence, 1983-1993 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and printed material 1974, 1985, undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Wail, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    One letter, originally in a folder of this title, to Kepes from someone named Muntadas (probably Antoni Muntadas).
  - Correspondence and printed material, 1977-1981 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence and printed material, 1954-1994 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    Bulk 1970s and 1980s. Vast bulk correspondence. A small amount of printed material and clippings.
  - Correspondence and clippings, 1982-1986 (Box 34, Folder 20)
    All in an unlabeled folder originally. Bulk correspondence, also includes clippings.
  - Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence and printed material, 1979-1981 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    Bulk correspondence. Publicity materials for artist Athena Tacha.
  - Correspondence, 1941-1995 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Polaroids, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    Letter and set of 10 Polaroid prints pasted to sheets of paper. Originally in manila envelope with this title. Polaroids are of various unlabeled artworks. They appear to have been included in an exhibition.
  - Correspondence, 1955-1992 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    Bulk 1970s. Also includes a few clippings.
  - Correspondence, 1974-1986 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and Printed Material, 1967-1987 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    Includes press release, annual reports.
  - Correspondence and printed material, 1951-1995 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    Bulk 1970s and 1980s. Bulk correspondence. Also contains printed material, clippings, and a small number of photographs
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    One letter from Francois de Vallombreuse to Kepes.
  - Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1997 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1988 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1975-1984 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1993 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1982 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    Some material in Hungarian.
  - Correspondence and printed material, 1978-1982 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    Bulk correspondence. Small amount of out-of-context printed material and one clipping. Some material in Hungarian.
  - Correspondence and printed material, 1971-1980 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    Bulk correspondence. Small amounts of clippings, publicity material, and printed material.
  - Correspondence and assorted material, 1971-1987 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    Bulk 1986-1987. Bulk correspondence.
  - Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1981 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1980 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    All but one item dated 1979-1980. Also contains a packet of photocopied drawings.
  - Correspondence and printed material, 1950-1995 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    Bulk 1970s and 1980s correspondence. Also contains a small amount of printed material, slides, and clippings.
  - Correspondence and printed material (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1977 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    Bulk 1976-1977. One letter from 1969 and one from 1975.
  - Prestini, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    Two letters from James Prestini about the Creators Equity Foundation.
  - Budapest, 1978 (Box 38, Folders 14-15)
    Some material in Hungarian. Correspondence and clippings.
  - Correspondence re: Palermo B. Russo, Projected Publications, 1975-1976 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Dartmouth College, 1977 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    Correspondence and printed material (a speech?).
  - Correspondence, National Academy of Design, 1976 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Takis - Paris, 1979-1981 (Box 38, Folder 20)
    Correspondence and printed material between Kepes and Takis Vassilakis.
  - Correspondence, Academy of Independent Scholars, 1979 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1977-1979 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Recommendations, 1978-1981 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Kunstlerhaus Mays, 1975-1976 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    Correspondence, some in German.
  - ICUS, 1975-1976 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    Correspondence and clippings related to the International Conference on the Unity of Sciences.
  - Correspondence, 1973-1981 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Bauhaus-Archiv, 1973-1975 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Rochester Institute of Technology, 1971-1972 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    Correspondence and photos.
  - Paintings in Collection (Box 78, Folders 3-4)
    Receipts and correspondence about G. Kepes Art Collection.
  - Art Objects (Box 78, Folders 5)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1963 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    Correspondents include "Don," William LeBrun, and Connie Breuer.
  - Otto Piene, Misc. Correspondence, 1967-1994 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Robert Smithson Correspondence, 1969 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Selected Correspondence 1, 1957-1980 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    Alphabetical by correspondent. Albers through Johnson on list of correspondents.
  - Selected Correspondence 2, 1943-1981 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    Alphabetical by correspondent. Kokoschka through Pei on list of correspondents.
  - Selected Correspondence 3, 1951-1988 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    Alphabetical by correspondent. Rebay to Wilson. Otto Piene in separate file (Folder 7).
  - Telegrams to Kepes from Daniel Catton Rich and Garrett Eckbo, 1944, 1947 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    Photocopies of correspondence, mostly from Maurice Kilbridge, the Dean of the Graduate School of Design.
  - Notable correspondence, 1945-2003 (Box 105, Folder 2)
    These letters may have been removed from other files and assembled here; however, not all of the correspondence may be considered especially noteworthy. Included here are letters from the following: Josef Albers 4/15/58; Buckminster Fuller 1/21/81 (photocopy); Walter Gropius 3/16/61; Philip Johnson 11/1/47; Lazlo Maholy-Nagy 9/20/45 (encouraging Kepes to contribute photos to his forthcoming "Vision in Motion" book); I.A. Richards 5/6/70; Erik Erikson, undated; Josep Luis Sert 7/10/69; Aaron Siskind 5/3/55; Edwards Steichen 4/6/61; Kenzo Tange 12/10/64; Robert Jay Wolff 8/7/74 (missing a page). There are also letters from San Francisco gallery owner Stephen Wirtz, Robert Brown of the Archives of American Art, and researcher Reinhold Martin to Kepes' daughter in 2003. Two outgoing drafts by Kepes are also present.
  - Trip to China (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - R. Buckminster Fuller open letter (unsigned), 1963-06-7 (Box 105, Folder 4)
- Series 15. Hungarian correspondence, publications, etc.
  - Hungarian Material, 1973-1987 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    Correspondence and printed material. Bulk Correspondence.
  - Hungarian Correspondence, Corume Budapest N.L., 1973-1974 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    Correspondence, clippings and printed material. Bulk Correspondence.
  - Bauhaus, 1977-1979 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Hungarian Material, 1979-1997 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    Correspondence, printed material, and clippings. Bulk Correspondence.
  - Other Hungarian, 1937-1996 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    Originally in a folder of this title. All in Hungarian. Correspondence and clippings. Bulk correspondence. Bulk 1976-1989.
  - Hungarian Consulate Letter, 2001 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    Letter from the Hungarian Consulate in New York to Kepes. In Hungarian.
  - Hungary, 1969-1975 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    All in Hungarian. Correspondence, clippings, and drawings. Bulk correspondence.